Let's add more detail to describe the relationship between a pair of stocks.
下面再详细讲解下股票对之间的关系
Recall that some time series such as stock prices are integrated of order one.
股价等时序是一阶积分
By this, I mean that if we take the time difference of this time series,
如果计算此时序的时间差分
we can get a stationary series.
将获得稳定的序列
When a series is stationary,
当序列稳定时
it is also integrated of order zero.
它就是零阶积分
Another way to get a stationery process is to
获取稳定序列的另一种方式是
find some linear combination of a pair of stocks.
寻找某种股票对的线性组合
For example, if stock X and stock Y have an economic link,
例如 如果股票 X 和股票 Y 有经济联系
then if we subtract one from the other,
那么如果用一个减去另一个
we may get a time series that is stationary.
将获得稳定的时序
More generally, we multiply X by hedge ratio using regression.
更一般的方法是 通过回归将 X 乘以对冲比率
Then we take Y minus the estimate of Y based on the hedge ratio and the value of X.
然后用 Y 减去根据对冲比率和 X 的值估算出的 Y
This difference is the spread.
这个差异称为价差
If the spread is stationary,
如果价差是稳定的
then it is integrated of order zero.
那么它是零阶积分
Also if the spread is stationary,
此外 如果价差是稳定的
then we say that the original series of X and Y are cointegrated.
那么我们说原始序列 X 和 Y 是协整关系
The hedge ratio is also called the coefficient of cointegration.
对冲比率也称为协整系数
Note that cointegration is not the same as correlation.
注意 协整与相关性不一样
Correlation is the covariance re-scaled to range from negative one to positive one.
相关性是范围重新调整到 -1 - 1 的方差
A strong positive correlation means that when stock A moves up,
强正相关表示当股票 A 上涨时
stock B moves up at the same time and vice versa.
股票 B 也上涨 反之亦然
However, if the magnitude of movement in one stock is greater than the other,
但是 如果一支股票的变化大小比另一支股票的大
then they can still drift apart even though they are correlated.
那么它们依然会分散 即使二者相关
In other words, two correlated stocks may not be cointegrated.
换句话说 两个相关的股票不一定协整
Cointegration means that, over a range of days,
协整是指在几天内
the relative increase in A is matched by a relative increase in B.
A 的相对增长与 B 的相对增长保持一致
Let's imagine that we use $100 to buy stock A and $100 to buy stock B.
假设我们用 100 美元买入股票 A 并用 100 美元买入股票 B
Assuming these are cointegrated,
假设这两个股票是协整关系
the value of both positions would remain similar over time.
两个头寸的值在一段时间内保持相似性
So keep in mind that a pair of stocks may be correlated but not cointegrated.
注意 一对股票可能相关 但不协整
Similarly, a pair of stocks may be cointegrated but not correlated.
同样 一对股票可能协整但不相关
For pairs trading, we want to find pairs of stocks that are cointegrated.
对于配对交易 我们希望寻找具有协整关系的股票
The method for checking if two series are cointegrated is called the Engle-Granger Test.
检查两个序列是否协整的方法称为 Engle-Granger 检验
The Engle-Granger Test involves two steps that we saw previously.
Engle-Granger 检验包含两步
One, find the hedge ratio using regression.
第一步是使用回归计算对冲比率
Two, calculate the spread and test if the spread is stationary.
第二步是计算价差并检验价差是否稳定
If the spread is stationary,
如果价差稳定
then the two series are cointegrated.
那么这两个序列是协整关系
To check if the spread is stationary,
我们将使用 Augmented Dickey-Fuller 检验
we use the Augmented Dickey-FullerTest.
检查价差是否稳定
The Augmented Dickey-Fuller Test outputs a P-value.
Augmented Dickey-Fuller 检验会输出一个p 值
If the P-value is small, say,
如果 p 值很小 例如等于或小于 0.05
0.05 or less, then we can assume that the spread is stationary.
那么我们可以认为价差是稳定的
Therefore, we can assume that the two are cointegrated.
所以可以认为这两个股票是协整关系